Hello programer, welcome back to today's SQL TQL series, so today we're going to explore the
various operators in the MySQL and simply define the operator in the SQL, the simple keyword
to perform operations in data, include arithmetic operator, comparison operator, logical operator
and more. So now let's explore for how they work with some example. So in the session, first of all,
I can just start with the arithmetic operator and this allows us to perform the mathematical
calculation in the SQL, okay. So now just define, so first of all, I can go for here this SQL
for the managed server management studio and first of all here, just type this the select.
Then now here, I can use the sum function and in this inside, I can define for
quantity, okay. Then use for the multiple sign and just type this is the unit, so even
IT unit price, okay. And use as the, get the new product for the sales, okay. And now here we have
to choose the sales table, okay. So different here perfectly and here I use the multiplication
operator to calculate the total sales by multiplying the quantity and the unit price column
for now, okay. And in this, the sample showed, so adds up these values to keep as the total sales,
okay. So now just select all in the data query and execute, you can see here the total sales
for the sales table, okay. So here I can create then other new query just open for the sales
for the table, okay. So now just select and just verify this. So from here,
this will be the sales table, okay. So now here complete and select for the execute, you can
see here the sales table for the row and the column information and here the total sales
resume, okay. I hope you understand it and this is completely done the arithmetic operator.
Next, I will field the comparison of that data used, okay. So just go here again
and now first of all, we are going to start select, remove this data query, okay.
So first of all, we can use the select and multiplication sign and you can choose from the
employee stable, okay. And next step here just use for the where the salary column
is greater than 50,000, okay. So here I have completely using for the greater than operator
and select the employee's because salary is greater than 50,000. And this query is written for
the row from the employee stable. So now just select and see the result in the display. So
you can see here perfectly see the result from the employee's ID, the name David and here the 35
and the salary range is 16,000 and the department office, okay. And here this query for the employee
stable for the salary is greater than for here use for the 50,000, okay. 50,000 greater than 60,000,
okay. So you can understand this perfectly. And the next step, we can use another operator now,
I'll create for the logical operator, okay. So the logical operator allows us to combine the
multiple condition in this query. So now simply just here I can use the select and now choose for
the table here, use the product table. So this is the product table and use the where and now just
here I can type this is the category. So defined for the category is equal to
use for the product name is camera, okay. And then use and operator and then define the price
column is greater than 500, okay. And now here completely new and this new appropriate select the
product from the camera category and we have the price greater than 500. And now just enter the first
select and going to execute and you can see here the product and I can give the price and the
category of the camera and the price here that basically, okay. So in this data query it's perfectly
written all the know from the product table that meet both condition, okay. So here completely
done for the school operator. So and there you have it. I can now try perfectly overview
of the various operations in the school with some practical example, okay. So I hope
you find this tutorial helpful. So stay tuned for more SQL tips and tricks, okay. So thank
you for watching and happy SQL data coding, okay.